# Sina Malek

Software Engineer

**US** Citizen

Active Secret Clearance

# **Personal Info**

Address

Tucson, Arizona, USA

Phone

(602)-471-7084

Email

maleksina1998@gmail.com

Website

www.sinamalek.com

# Skills

Python

C/C++

**CMake** 

**MATLAB** 

SCPI, YAML

Markdown, Doxygen

Git

### **Software**

**IDEs** 

Microsoft Visual Studio Visual Studio Code PyCharm Workbench MATLAB

### Miscellaneous

Clonezila Beyond Compare NI-MAX

#### Microsoft Office

Excel PowerPoint OneNote Outlook Word Experienced software engineer in need of a full-time direct hire position with a dynamic company. Resolute collaborator with strong ethics who can work independently or with a team. Has experience in test software and architecture, embedded programming, clean up, automation and producing standardizations for future software developments.

# **Experience**

2021-05 -Present

#### Software Engineer I

Raytheon Missile & Defense / Tucson, AZ

- Configured oscilloscopes, signal generators, signal analyzers, power supplies, FSWP, RF switch boxes to be compatible with internal software and able to communicate using SCPI and Python scripts to programs specifications.
- Automated BIT process to ensure health of hardware by using Azure DevOps, YAML and Python scripts. Reduced human errors when performing tests.
- Saved the company time by reducing the number of hours needed when testing and delivering hardware stacks to programs. Created **automated** system to improve testing standard.
- Trained basic regression neural network with Henze-Penrose Divergence loss. Converted existing MATLAB scripts to Python and used existing NumPy data sets to determine loss.
- Updated software version through merge techniques and tools such as Beyond Compare and ensuring the entirety of the software remained functional.
- Established backlog, work items and sprint velocities, functioned as **Scrum Master** for team and product.

2019-05 -2019-10

#### IT Service Desk Intern

Amkor Technology Inc. / Tempe, AZ

- **Project leader** of Windows 7 to Windows 10 conversion for Tempe location.
- Collaborated with various departments to utilize **Clonezilla** to create standard computer image.
- Assisted in IT services to increase company output by providing technology support for all users; ensure users workstations function to company standard, and have thoroughly documented results for future reference.
- Implemented configuration and deployment of new equipment such as laptops, desktops, and phones.

# **Education**

2016-05 -2020-05

# Bachelor of Science in Engineering Computer Systems

Arizona State University / Tempe, AZ

- Graduated Cum Laude, 3.5 / 4.0
- Software Officer for Naval Research Laboratory CanSat competition. Placed **first** amongst US teams.
- Studied Al/ML, OS, software architecture, networking, and embedded systems.